[The Heir]
[Episode 17]
You are just a merchant.
How can you act on behalf of His Majesty?
Qi Jiu, your action is truly overstepping.
Besides,
normally, if a commoner
wants to report an official,
they either file a petition
on the day of filing,
or beat the drum of grievance.
You did neither of these.
Qi Jiu,
you are seriously not taking
His Majesty's rules
seriously.
Lord He.
Zhao Shen is the magistrate of She County.
Both of those options
must go through him.
If I were to alert him
and he destroys the evidence,
the truth will never come to light.
Moreover, you may not know this.
We are in Huizhou
under Marshal Qi's orders
to purchase military supplies.
What I am doing
is also to rid the people of an evil.
And as far as I know,
you have always been just and upright,
never associating
with those corrupt officials
in the court.
Isn't that so, Lord He?
Of course.
I didn't expect you
to have such an identity.
It was my oversight.
Apologies for that.
Rest assured.
I will carefully investigate this case
and give you
and Marshal Qi an explanation.
Thank you, Lord He.
[Zhao's Mansion]
My Lord.
Who's in charge of this place's
accounting?
I am.
You?
Well, My Lord.
She is the eldest daughter
of the Tian family.
I am Xu Chengde,
the accountant of Tian Ink Workshop.
How can I help you?
Where is the accounting room?
It's in the backyard.
Listen!
Take him away.
You two, go inside
and take all the ledgers.
Wh-What's going on?
Wait, My Lord.
What law has our family broken?
You don't know?
Colluding with corrupt official Zhao Shen
to seize private houses.
Secretly colluding with banks
to make a profit from loans.
These things,
Miss Tian, you should know better than us.
Lord He has ordered
to arrest the three men
of the Tian family.
As for the accountant
and the account books,
they will be taken
to the government office and detained.
You should probably
close your store today.
Let's see how
Lord He's investigation goes.
Take them away!
My Lord.
Mr. Xu!
My Lord! My Lord!
My Lord...
Go!
Lightly!
Hurry up!
That hurt!
Mind your manners!
Behave yourself!
Master!
Don't move.
Father!
Father.
What is going on here?
Daughter,
you've seen what's going on?
The Tian family is over.
Only you can save me
and your two brothers.
Cut the crap.
Take him away!
What's going on?
Go!
-Master!
-Father!
Master!
Get back.
Mother!
What's going on?
Sister!
The men of the Tian family
have been taken away by the guards.
I've been waiting for this day...
for way too long.
I know.
Look how happy you are.
Come.
Sister,
thank you for
bearing with me recently.
Today, substituting tea for wine,
I toast you.
Good tea, as expected.
Every time I drink tea with you,
I feel my good tea is wasted.
I'm happy.
So happy.
The Tian family's father and sons
have been taken away by the government.
They are now trapped.
You can finally consider yourself avenged.
I am happy for you too.
Now, you should be at ease
and focus on proper business.
Yes.
But a centipede dies hard.
I'm only worried that the Tian family
has a backup plan.
Ronghua, what should we do?
You have to think of a way.
Your father and brother are in trouble.
What will we do in the future?
We must find a way
to save your father and brothers.
Nothing can happen to them.
If something happens to them,
how will the two of us live?
I've been helping in the accounting room
these past few years.
The Tian family's accounts
are clear and detailed—
I handled them all too.
They have absolutely nothing to do
with Zhao Shen.
Have you forgotten
what your father told you?
The accounts you made
can only fool idiots.
Do you think with your accounts,
we are able to top Hui Ink?
Mother...
What do you mean by that?
Have you forgotten how
the Luo family fell?
After the Luo family fell,
how their belongings
were sent to Lord Zhao's mansion?
And how the official silver
over the years
smoothly ended up
in his pockets?
Every single one of these things
could cost
your father and brothers their heads.
Ronghua.
We must think of a way.
We have to save your father and brothers.
If they really can't come back,
I really don't know how I'll live.
Ronghua, please save them.
Your father and brothers
cannot be in trouble,
do you understand?
Save them.
Master!
Ronghua...
Stop crying.
I said stop crying.
Th-There is a way?
Pack our things.
We're going to the capital.
Really?
Ronghua, you are agreeing?
Okay.
I will pack our bags right now.
Go,
pack young lady's bags.
Zhen.
Something happened.
What's wrong, Mother?
I just went to Butcher Zhang's
to buy meat.
I heard something happened
to the Tian family.
Tian Ink Workshop was sealed off.
Tian Huai'an and his sons
were also taken to the yamen together.
Mother, take your time.
What happened?
I just went around
to Tian Ink Workshop to take a look.
There were official seals
on its doors.
I also heard
they took away an accountant.
Who else did they take?
What about Ronghua? Is she okay?
I don't think it was Ronghua.
I heard it was an old man
surnamed Xu.
Mother, please keep an eye
on the ink workshop for me.
I'll go find Ronghua.
Zhen, slow down!
[Changsheng Garden]
Where is Ronghua?
Where is your lady?
You're finally here.
My Lady is going to marry
the dumb grandson
of the Capital's Lord Xu.
Go and persuade her!
Is she inside?
She is.
Ronghua!
Zhen.
What's going on?
I'm going to the Capital.
The Capital?
Are you really going to marry Lord Xu's
dumb grandson?
No.
You can't ruin your life like this.
There's no other way.
Three years ago,
our family rose to power
by stepping on the Luo family,
growing bigger step by step.
Three years later,
our ink workshop's raided
for a crime we committed.
My father and brothers
will be punished by law.
Maybe...
this is the Tian family's retribution.
They deserve it.
They may deserve it,
but not you.
I'm also a member of the Tian family.
Since something happened
to the Tian family,
what good could happen to me?
Zhen, I've envied you since we were kids.
When we were little,
you were the young lady
spoiled by your whole family.
Later, even when your family declined,
your grandfather, your brother,
and your mother
still treated you with all their hearts.
No matter what you want to do,
you can achieve it
as long as you work hard.
No matter what happens,
you can fight to the end.
Ronghua, you can do it too.
Don't worry.
With me around,
no one can force you to go to the Capital.
Zhen.
I'm not forced to go
to the Capital this time.
I am doing it willingly.
Ronghua...
You better think this through.
Going to the Capital
is bound to be
jumping into another fire pit.
Even if it's a fire pit,
I have to jump in there.
I can't just watch
my father and brothers lose their lives.
Ronghua.
Zhen.
You have your path to take,
and I have mine.
This is my fate.
I accept it.
After today,
we may never see each other again.
May everything
go well for you in the future.
Never be like me—
bowing your head to others.
Ronghua, it's time to go.
Ronghua.
Ronghua!
[Post]
Zhao Shen,
Lord Zhao.
I am here to see you off.
Master Qi.
You and I have no enmity
in the past or present.
Why are you causing me demise?
I'm causing you demise?
Lord Zhao,
if you want to talk about demise,
you only have yourself to blame.
You can only blame the fact
that over the years,
you've gotten too close
to the Tian family.
Lord Zhao.
Go to Jinling and await your execution.
You
and the father and sons
of the Tian family—
none of you will escape.
You!
You...
Xiao Qi.
[Capital, Hu's Mansion]
Smile.
[Lord Xu's grandson, Hu Qi]
Smile. Father, smile.
[Lord Xu's daughter, Xu Wan]
Are you getting used to the Capital?
Yes, yes.
Thank you, Madam.
Qi, be good.
Massage.
Young Master is quite lively.
Qi.
Be careful.
Mother.
Qi,
[Lord Xu's son-in-law, Hu Shiyuan]
be good.
Eat.
There's a lot of meat on the table,
eat more.
Thank you, Madam.
Ronghua,
it's a blessing of three lifetimes
for us to marry into the Hu family.
The Madam and the Lord are so good to us,
and Young Master is also a fine young man.
After you marry into the family,
you must be doubly considerate
to your husband,
understand?
Madam.
Ronghua is a good child.
I think she and Young Master
are destined for each other.
It seems
she really is a good child.
Yes.
Thank you for the compliment, Madam.
Just stay here with peace of mind.
Come.
Thank you, Madam.
Thank you, Lord.
Thank you! Thank you!
Thank you!
Ronghua, I hope you are well.
Our last hasty farewell
still feels like yesterday.
I wonder if you are doing well
in the Capital.
The noble mansions have strict etiquette,
so remember to be careful in your actions.
But if someone bullies you,
don't compromise.
There is always a way out.
I wish you all the best.
Run slower,
don't fall again.
Slowly, slowly.
Get up. Are you okay?
My knee hurts! My knee!
My knee!
Are you okay?
Don't sit on the ground, it's cold.
It's cold.
Are you hurt?
It hurts.
It doesn't hurt anymore.
Drum!
I want the drum.
Drum—
Don't move, I'll get it.
Drum.
Here.
Drum!
Have something to eat.
Eat.
Yum.
Eat slowly.
Don't choke.
Have some tea.
Eat.
It's not bad to be a fool.
You can do whatever you want.
Eat slowly.
Slowly.
Madam.
Have a seat.
Do you know why I called you here?
Please enlighten me, Madam.
I have seen how
you interact with Qi.
I ask myself:
even as his biological mother,
I can't help but despise a fool.
Those who can endure this much
are either deeply scheming
with ulterior motives,
or pure and innocent.
Which one
are you?
Naturally, I have a motive
to be willing to take care
of the Young Master
for the rest of his life.
My father and two older brothers
are in jail
for bribing the magistrate.
I came to the capital
to save them.
You are quite honest.
Your family
married you to a fool.
Don't you resent it?
Even a saint
would have some complaints
if met with a situation like this.
But I must repay my parents
for raising me.
Foolish filial piety.
Madam, as a mother,
with a loving heart,
naturally you'd hope to find someone
who is willing to take care
of the Young Master for the rest
of his life you can control.
Someone like me
is the most suitable.
I've always wanted a daughter,
but I couldn't get one.
When you marry Qi
and call me Mother,
you'll be no different
from my own daughter.
Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you...
Mother.
Here.
Father.
At a time like this,
aren't you anxious?
What's there to be anxious about?
You look like a loser.
You useless thing.
How can I not be anxious?
Lord Zhao has fallen.
What will happen to our family?
Are we going to stay here forever?
The fate of the Tian family
depends on that official in the capital.
Madam Hu,
I've come to say goodbye.
[To Magistrate He]
This is the letter Madam Hu
requested from Lord Xu.
With this letter,
my father and brothers
should be able to get out of trouble.
Thank you, Madam...
for saving the Tian family from disaster.
Ronghua,
when you stay in Hu's Mansion,
you must take good care of your husband.
Serve Madam well,
and don't make her angry.
Understand?
Madam, I entrust Ronghua
to you.
Don't worry.
Ronghua is so obedient.
In the future,
I will certainly love her
like my own daughter.
Thank you, Madam.
Mother,
let me walk you back
to change your clothes.
[Ronghua, I hope you are well.
Waiting for your reply, Li Zhen]
My Lady,
the food has been out for a while.
It's getting cold.
You should eat something first.
I'm not hungry. Clear it away.
My Lady,
you've read these letters
countless times.
Would you like to reply?
Lord He.
Master Tian, what a clever move.
I have received
the letter from the capital,
written by Lord Xu.
Lord He, the Tian family
is really wrongly accused.
Wrongly accused?
The account books
confiscated from your Tian family
completely does not match
the ink merchants' purchase orders.
Your family is clearly using
the ink business
to launder illicit money for Zhao Shen.
Although Lord Xu has already
shown some concern over this matter,
the evidence is irrefutable.
How could I
bend the law for personal gain?
You are absolutely right, Lord He.
How could our Tian family
make things difficult for you?
However, My Lord,
our Tian family
was indeed deceived by a villain.
My father is not fully literate.
He mistakenly trusted the accountant,
Xu Chengde,
and entrusted all business funds to him.
We didn't expect
that this man would collude with Zhao Shen
and frame our Tian family.
Since a mistake was made,
someone has to take the responsibility.
The Tian family will not tolerate it.
Xu Chengde is entirely at your disposal.
Eldest Young Master Tian,
well played.
The crime is established
and the culprit is found.
Tell me,
how should I punish him?
You are very thoughtful, My Lord.
Our Tian family cannot shirk
our responsibility this time.
We will definitely set an example
to warn others.
Since a mistake was made,
we must accept the punishment.
You can confiscate the 5,000 taels
of illicit money.
As illicit money,
confiscating it is only natural.
My Lord,
you are absolutely right.
In addition,
our Tian family will offer
another 1,000 taels of silver
to the Huizhou government office
as efforts to set an example
for operation of the ink business
and restore integrity to the industry.
We will have to trouble you
with this matter, Lord He,
which will also
protect your good reputation.
Right, My Lord?
Eldest Young Master Tian,
as someone this scheming,
your talents are wasted here.
You must be joking, My Lord.
Master Tian.
As the Prefect of Huizhou,
I hope your Tian family will
behave yourselves in the future.
Definitely.
Definitely, definitely.
The Tian family's
savings over all these years
are gone just like that.
Father.
The only thing we can do now
is to cut off our arm to save ourselves.
Where there is life,
there is hope.
[Huizhou Prefecture Office]
Tian Huai'an,
what do you
have to say?
Prefect.
I was momentarily confused
and employed the wrong person.
Zhao Shen is a shameless scoundrel.
Xu Chengde
looks honest,
but he is actually an
insatiably greedy person.
The two of them secretly colluded
over false accounts.
I
knew absolutely nothing.
Master, you... you...
My Lord.
My Lord!
Mr. Xu.
You watched
the three of us siblings grow up.
The Tian family has always
trusted you immensely.
Your son
and grandson
both work at Tian Ink.
Our family respects you as an elder
and treats your family
as if they were our own.
How...
How could you trap the Tian family
in such an unjust position?
Xu Chengde.
Do you plead guilty
to colluding with Zhao Shen
to cook
the books?
My Lord,
I...
I... I plead guilty.
I plead guilty.
My Lord.
As the master of Tian Ink,
I know I am at fault too.
I voluntarily resign as master of Tian Ink
as punishment.
From now on,
I will never
enter the Huizhou ink industry again.
Very well.
Since Tian Huai'an
has penalized himself
and withdrawn
from the Huizhou ink industry,
I hereby sentence
the criminal
Xu Chengde
to exile in the North.
The Tian family is to return
5,000 taels of illicit money.
The 3 Tian family men
are acquitted
and released.
Court dismissed!
Lord He.
There is one thing I don't understand.
The Tian family colluded with Zhao Shen
in corruption.
Why were they acquitted and released?
Master Qi.
The witnesses and material evidence
all point to
Zhao Shen's corruption.
His accountant, Xu Chengde,
has confessed
that he was the one
who colluded with Zhao Shen.
The Tian family was unaware of it.
Lord He,
do you really believe
such a claim?
Master Qi.
Judging a case
requires evidence.
Even if
there might be
other claims,
a final conviction
still depends on evidence.
I doubt your judgement
will convince the public.
As a local magistrate,
you should plead for the people
and be just and incorruptible.
As I just said,
I only judge cases
based on evidence.
And
it has always been so.
Lord He.
Is it truly impossible
to overturn this case?
Master Qi,
figure it out yourself.
I advise you
not to cause trouble
for Marshal Qi.
Sorry to bother you, Lord He.
The Emperor's edict to the ink merchants
and citizens of Huizhou.
Now,
I seek the finest ink in the world
for the exclusive use
of the imperial court.
All Tribute Ink
judged as top quality by the court
will be heavily rewarded
to encourage the ink trade
to continue improving its skills.
I
know there are many scholars
and men of letters in the world—
some may possess precious ink,
or have unique skills.
I hope you all understand my intentions,
and enthusiastically offer ink,
to jointly support
this grand literary event
and leave a legacy for eternity.
That's the edict—
in the 42nd year of Jiajing.
Long live...
His Majesty.
Long live
Everyone.
The Emperor's grace is vast.
This time's
Tribute Ink selection
allows for every family with prized ink
to join.
All those who are shortlisted
will be posted on the notice board
in Sibao Street.
As you all know,
the right to produce
Tribute Ink in Huizhou
has fallen into the hands
of others for years.
This is an opportunity
we cannot miss again.
Whether we can
get the Tribute Ink rights back...
depends on all of you.
Sacrificing his daughter
for personal gain...
How shameless!
Let's stop here.
Lord Xu is the Grand Secretariat.
This matter involves the imperial court.
Lord Xu is the one
protecting the Tian family now.
If you keep pushing,
you'll be openly challenging Lord Xu.
Think about your own identity.
If you go against Lord Xu,
how do you expect General to handle it?
Let me remind you once more:
the Tian family has been cleared
of their charges
and regained their qualification
to run for the Tribute Ink.
If the Tian family wins the right,
the orders for Hui Ink
will all start going to them.
Your dividends in Li Ink
will definitely be affected.
Brother, you must know.
Your six-month deadline
with General is approaching.
If it really comes to that,
your plans in the ink industry
will be completely ruined.
You'd better think about
what's the most important thing now.
You are right, Sister.
I was too impulsive just now.
The most urgent task right now
is the Tribute Ink.
So what's your plan?
Even though Lord Xu
can interfere in official affairs,
he might not be able to control
the Tribute Ink competition.
The Tian family is clinging to Lord Xu
just to find a bigger backer.
As long as it's a backer,
it has to be supported with silver.
Then I'll find a way
to cut off their way of making money
through Tribute Ink.
Over time,
when the money is gone,
this Lord Xu
naturally won't help
the Tian family anymore.
I have to find a way to win
the rights to the Tribute Ink.
First, that'll help
with the military funds.
Second,
to cut off the Tian family's retreat.
I'm relieved that you
can think this far.
My Lord, you just said congratulations,
but I wonder
what's there to congratulate
the Li family for.
Old Madam.
The Tribute Ink selection this time—
the timing, location, and people—
are all in favor of the Li family.
That's worth congratulating.
Lord Yan.
The Li family is still thinking
about the Tribute Ink selection.
We haven't officially registered yet.
Is there
some misunderstanding?
There is no misunderstanding.
I was involved in the restoration
of the ancient lacquer-soot ink
from the
very beginning to the end.
At the ink testing event,
I saw its brilliance with my own eyes.
Therefore,
I selected the ancient lacquer-soot ink
as the primary selection ink
of the Li family personally.
Such good ink
will definitely be on the list.
As for
the final selection...
Lord Yan,
I have been
working hard to research and improve
the Yunsong Ink in recent years.
I am confident
to participate
in the Tribute Ink selection
with the new Yunsong Ink.
The new Yunsong Ink?
Yes.
There must've been a huge improvement.
Where is the ink?
It is still being improved.
I believe it will be
finished soon.
How many days is soon?
That's inappropriate.
This Tribute Ink selection
is not a trivial matter after all.
If you sign up
with an unfinished ink,
it's a little inappropriate.
Old Madam.
Have a look.
Please.
Everyone's familiar
with this ink, right?
This is Miss Li Zhen's Fu Jin Ink.
To be honest,
this piece of Fu Jin Ink from Miss Li Zhen
cured my daughter's chronic disease.
An ink
that can cure people
winning the Tribute Ink selection
is inevitable, isn't it?
But, My Lord,
although this Fu Jin Ink
is great...
it is not an ink of the Li family.
Lord Yan,
I am extremely grateful
for your painstaking efforts.
The Eighth Branch to which Zhen belongs
has long been expelled from the family.
She is now the Head of New Li Ink.
She has nothing to do
with Li Ink.
I have also heard
about the Tribute Ink turmoil
and the expulsion of the Eighth Branch
of the Li family.
But that was in the past.
The past is the past,
now is now—
times have changed.
I see
Miss Li Zhen has been cooperating closely
with the Li family recently.
This is a good thing.
Why not
take advantage
of the Tribute Ink selection
to combine the New Li and main Li
into one.
That'd be a great thing
to the ink industry.
Why not, right?
My Lord,
Li Ink is an expert at pine soot.
In the past,
we'd submit pine soot ink
for Tribute Ink selection.
To change the type of ink so abruptly
is a little...
I understand
everything you say and think.
It's fine.
Don't be constrained
by these minor details.
To be honest,
I have already sent for Miss Li Zhen.
When she arrives,
let's settle this matter here.
Please rescind your order, Lord Yan!
Lord Yan,
I thank you
for your appreciation.
However, this ancient lacquer-soot ink
has nothing to do
with New Li Ink Workshop.
Before this,
I was just an ink maker
hired by the Li family.
As for this Fu Jin Ink,
I had no intention
of submitting it for selection.
My ambition does not lie in Tribute Ink.
I ask for your understanding.
Miss Li Zhen,
what do you mean by this?
Rights to Tribute Ink
is what an ink maker
seeks all their life.
You say your ambition does not lie there—
very well.
Tell me,
where does your ambition lie, then?
I am content to be able to
open New Li Ink Workshop,
make ink,
and support my family.
I dare not aim for
the right to Tribute Ink.
Miss Li Zhen.
Your abilities
and courage—
I have seen them for myself.
You are by no means
a person lacking ambition.
There's no need to be modest.
I am not being modest.
Our Eighth Branch's
expulsion from the family,
my father's death,
and how my entire family was left
to wander around City Gate Lane
was all because of Tribute Ink.
Although I love ink
and also consider making ink
as a lifelong ambition,
I don't want to...
have anything to do with Tribute Ink
ever again.
I beg for your understanding, Lord Yan.
Li Zhen!
What a lot of excuses.
What a lot of difficulties.
Are my good intentions
causing a bad thing instead?
Please calm down, My Lord.
In that case,
I'll put it bluntly!
No matter what happened,
Huizhou must win
the Tribute Ink selection!
I will personally
present it to His Majesty!
Your Li family
can't refuse!
Everyone,
know your place.